Register of the Benton Weaver Decker Papers, 1916-1980
Hoover Institution Archives
Benton Weaver Decker Papers,
1916-1980
74102
Hoover Institution Archives
9 manuscript boxes, 2 envelopes (3.8 linear feet)
Correspondence, speeches and writings, orders, citations, memorabilia, clippings, and other printed matter, relating to U.S. occupation forces in Japan, and U.S. foreign relations in the Far East.
Decker, Benton Weaver, 1899-1983.
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Biographical/Historical note
Rear admiral, United States Navy; commander, Yokosuka Naval Base, Japan, 1946-1950.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1974, with additional increments thorough 1983.
Scope and Contents note
Correspondence, speeches and writings, orders, citations, memorabilia, clippings, and other printed matter, relating to American occupation forces in Japan, and American foreign relations in the Far East.
United States. Naval Base (Yokosuka, Japan); United States. Navy--Officers.; East Asia--Foreign relations--United States.; East Asia.; Japan--History--Allied occupation, 1945-1952.; Japan.; United States--Armed Forces.; United States--Foreign relations--East Asia.; United States--Foreign relations.; World War, 1939-1945--Naval operations.; World War, 1939-1945.
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1936-1973
  Scope and Contents note
  Arranged alphabetically by correspondent
  - Acheson, Barclay, 1950, 1951 (Box 1)
  - American National Red Cross, 1957, 1960-1961
  - American Tunaboat Association, 1961
  - Backman, C. E., 1950-1954
  - Bate, John, 1952
  - Brines, Russell, 1953
  - Brown, Edmund G., 1959
  - Bull, S. L., 1952
  - Burke, Arleigh, Admiral, 1958
  - Burlingham, Hupper and Kennedy, 1960
  - Busik, W. S., 1973
  - Carney, R. B., Admiral, 1953
  - Chase, William C., Major General, 1951
  - Coyle, Ray W., 1955
  - Crawford, George G., 1956
  - Dyer, George C., 1964
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D., 1952
  - Fine Arts Gallery of San Diego, 1960-1962
  - Gantt, W. E., 1973
  - General Headquarters Supreme Commander for the Allied Powers, 1950-1951
  - Herter, Christian A., Jr., 1953
  - Hickey, Doyle O., Major General, 1951
  - Horn, Roy De S., 1950
  - Institute on World Affairs, 1956
  - International News Service, 1953
  - Joy, C. T., Vice Admiral, 1950
  - Kanto Auto Works, 1965
  - Kenyon, Cecil, n.d.
  - Kilbimy, Ted, 1951
  - Knight, Goodwin J., 1955
  - Knowland, William F., 1951-1958
  - Kraft, Fred H., 1955
  - Ladow, C. R., 1953
  - Life, 1961
  - Luckel, Frank, 1959
  - MacArthur, Douglas, General, 1955
  - Mariner Ship Admiral Decker, 1960
  - Mariner Troop II, 1960
  - McKibben, C. A., 1964
  - McLean, H. H., Rear Admiral, 1950
  - McQuilken, John, 1955
  - Mundt, Karl E., 1953
  - Navy Relief Society, 1933, 1938
  - Nixon, Richard, 1950-1956
  - Pratt, Albert, 1954
  - Price, Admiral, 1959
  - Ramallo, E., 1959-1968
  - Republican National Committee, 1956
  - Robinson, James I., 1959
  - Robinson, Ray C., 1955
  - Rogers, William P., 1955
  - San Diego Chamber of Commerce, 1957
  - San Diego County Republican Central Committee, 1954
  - San Diego Yacht Club, 1950, 1961
  - Shearer, William K., 1956, 1957
  - Shimada, Kanji, 1966
  - Smith, Alexander H., 1954, 1956
  - Stratemeyer, George E., Lt. General, 1962
  - Streibert, Theodore C., 1956
  - Swartz, Ray, 1968
  - Swing, Joseph M., General, 1956
  - Tait, Edward T., 1956
  - Trau, E. F., 1954
  - United States Atomic Energy Commission, 1958
  - United States Naval Academy, 1951
  - Vossler, F. A. L., 1936, 1937
  - Wagner, Paul F., 1954
  - Waters, Laughlin, E., 1952
  - Weinberer, Caspar W., 1957, 1958
  - Wilson, Bob, 1955-1960
  - Withington, F. S., 1959
  - Yokosuka City Hall, 1962
  - Yorkrite Masonic Bodies, 1966
  - Miscellaneous, 1938-1966
- SUBJECT FILE, 1916-1965
  Awards, citations, orders, appointments, commissions, and printed matter, arranged as listed
  - Awards, citations, and presentations, 1921-1965 (Box 1)
  - Biographical sketch of Rear Admiral Benton W. Decker, 1899-1949
  - "The Last 100 Years," by Joan Obermeyer, unpublished history of the Yokosuka Naval Base, n.d.
  - Orders, appointments, and commissions, 1916-1955
  - Perry painting presented to the Naval Academy Museum, 1952 (Box 2)
  - "The Sacramento Slam," weekly news letters from the U.S.S. Sacramento, 1929
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1952-1954
  Articles, lectures and speeches, arranged alphabetically by title
  - "The Admirals Go To Sea," by Rear Admiral B. W. Decker, n.d. (Box 2)
  - "Detention in Korea," article by Admiral B. W. Decker, special correspondent for International News Service
  - "Masonry in Japan," by B. W. Decker, The New Age, Washington, D.C., 1954
  - "Our Future in Asia," lecture by Admiral B. W. Decker, 1952
  - "Selection of Enlisted Men for the Naval Academy," by Lieutenant B. W. Decker, n.d.
  - "Youth and America," speech to the Daughters of the American Revolution, by Admiral B. W. Decker, 1954
- MISCELLANEOUS, 1946-1972
  - 6 albums with newspaper clippings of Admiral B. W. Decker as Commanding Officer at Yokosuka Naval Base, 1946-1950 (Box 3)
  - Printed material concerning Admiral B. W. Decker, 1946-1972
- PHOTOGRAPHS (Envelope A-B)
  Depicts American landing craft repair facilities in the Russell Islands group within the Solomon Islands during World War II. (67 prints / 2 envelopes)
- INCREMENT - February 1977
  - "The Yokosuka Story, or The Return of the Black Ships," by B. W. and Edwina Decker, 1976, 1946-1950 (Box 4)
- INCREMENT - September 1979
  - Orders, correspondence, reports and memoranda, relating to American administration of Yokosuka Naval Base, Japan., 1946-1950 (Box 5-7.)
- INCREMENT - May 1983
  - Orders, clippings, and other printed matter, memorabilia, and photographs, relating to the visit of U.S. Naval personnel to Japan, 1939 (Box 8)
- INCREMENT - August 1983
  - Two scrapbooks of clippings relating to Admiral Decker's activities during World War I (Box 9)
  - Typescript manuscript by Joseph F. Enright, entitled "The Secret Life of a Giant Warship,", 1980